FRANK LUSE

SOFTWARE & DATA ENGINEER

EXPERTISE

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, GraphQL, C++, Java

LIBRARIES & FRAMEWORKS

React, jQuery, Express, Pandas, Numpy

TOOLS & PLATFORMS

AWS, Git, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Stata, Node.js

DESIGN

Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign

EDUCATION

BA IN ECONOMICS BA IN SOCIOLOGY

The University of Kansas Honors Program

2017 - 2021 ; CGPA: 3.96

OTHER

LANGUAGES

English, Spanish

VOLUNTEERING

Kansas Permaculture Institute Boy Scouts of America KU Campus Beautification Initiative

ACHIEVEMENTS

Eagle Scout Honors Distinction

CONTACT

fluseg@gmail.com

(773) 383-1129 (

frankluse.com 🏠

github.com/fluse9

linkedin.com/in/frankluse in



PROFILE

I am a young software engineer and entrepreneur with experience in a fastpaced startup. I had sole responsibility for all data engineering and successfully oversaw product and business development resulting in getting a product to market. With experience in software and a strong knowledge of statistics, I specialize in developing ready-to-ship web applications and data pipelines.

EXPERIENCE

TERRAFARM | FROM OCT 2019 - Present Co-Founder and Chief Executive Officer

- · Led 4 engineering teams and 1 design team from development to launch
- Developed an in-home vertical farm OS using C++ and Python that controls farm actuators and accesses database systems in real time
- · Created a user-web application in React.js, Node.js, and GraphQL that allows customers to record what they plant and harvest and control certain actuators
- · Constructed real time data pipelines to store thousands of customer and farm data points every day using AWS hosted PostgreSQL and MongoDB instances

THE UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS | FROM JAN 2019 - MAY 2020 Math Tutor - Applied Statistics

- Tutored small groups of up to 5 students in elementary and applied statistics
- · Guided students through course material, created practice problems, helped students improve their skills in probability, statistical analysis, and regression

PROJECTS

HONORS THESIS IN SOCIOLOGY | FROM AUG 2020 - Present

• Studied the effectiveness of OECD countries' stimulus programs in the 2020 recession using OLS linear regression and logistic regression models

AUTOMATED STOCK TRADING BOT | FROM OCT 2020 - DEC 2020

- Used Pandas, Numpy, and OLS regression to find predictors of stock returns
- · Developed a Python bot to execute trades on Robinhood & Alpaca using triple momentum, divergence, and relative strength strategies

JARVIS PERSONAL ASSISTANT | FROM DEC 2020 - Present

 Created a personal assistant using Python and natural language processing that interprets commands and queries websites for its responses

FLUSE (MUSIC PRODUCER) | FROM AUG 2016 - Present

- · Composed, recorded, and produced original songs and remixes
- · Created logos, album art, and promotional materials
- · Achieved over 1 million streams on all streaming platforms combined